A Guide to the John Z. Bowers papers FA1415
Rockefeller Archive Center
- The Health of Mankind, 5.5 Cubic Feet
  - Unlabeled Folder (Box 17, Folder 424)
    "The Division of the Biological Sciences, THe University of Chicago, 1949-1962; Biological Sciences Development Informal History" by Lowell T. Coggleshall; "A Conceptual Model of Program Implementation for Improving Nutritional Status of the Rural Poor in THailand, Part I. Implementation of a Conceptual Scheme in the Village of Nong-Hai, Northeast Thailand" by Sakorn Dhanamitta, Suwanee Virojailee, and Aree Valyasevi; "The Ramathibodi Community Health Program: A Brief Study"; Program, Fred L. Soper Memorial; "Dr. Carlos J. Finlay and the 'Hall of Fame' of New York"; Stampar Photograph; Andrija Stampar Encyclopedia Entry; "Observations of a Rural Health Worker" by Andrija Stampar; "Sixth Award of the Leon Bernard Foundation Prize (to Stampar); Ida M. Cannon: Pioneer in Medical Social Work" by Harriett M. Bartlett
  - YARU [Yale Arbovirus Research Unit] (Box 17, Folder 425)
    Notes and Photocopies from Rockefeller Foundation; Grant Actions for Yale University - School of Medicine - Arbovirus Research Unit (1964-1967); "Memorandum Sent to Trustees February 8, 1961, and Discussed at Meeting of hte Board on April 5, 1961"; "Inventory for The Rockefeller Foundation Virus Laboratories, New York, NY" (1963); "Agreement between The Rockefeller Foundation and Yale University Concerning the Location of the Central Laboratories of the Virus Research Program in a University Building (Preliminary Draft)"; "Instituto 'Adolfo Luiz' Virus Department, Arbor Virus Laboratory, Sao Paulo, Brazil, 1961-1962"
  - Medical Education (Box 17, Folder 426)
    "The Rockefeller Benefaction" by G. Blacker; Correspondence; "The Wilkie Research Department"; "Review of Grants in the Maritime Provinces of Canada and in Newfoundland, 1911-1933" by RObert M. Lester
  - PUMC [Peking Union Medical College] Illustrations (Box 17, Folder 427)
    Khati Lim with her brother and his family; Old/new midwifery equipment; Foreign-trained graduate nurses; Dr. J.P. Maxwell; Class work in practical anatomy; 1925 The Auditorium; John B. Grant; Donald Van Slyke; Members of the Department of Medicine; Franklin C. McLean, 1919; Carl Ten Broeck; S.H. Zia, H.L. Chung, S.M. Tao, T.J. Kurotchin, C.E. Lim, Sam C. Wong, P.Y. Liu, W.T. Lieu, Richard H.P. Sia, C.C. Yang, C.T. Wu, H.M. Tchang, T. Tung, K.H. Pang; Nurses on duty, maternity ward; Robert Lim; Dr. Marion Yang; Prince Yu's Palace; Nieh Yu-Ch'an; Surgical ward – Dr. Taylor making a dressing; Examination; Class of old-style midwives; Dr. O.H. Robertson, Professor of Medicine; Harold Loucks; J. Heng Liu, Superintendent of the Hospital; Chu Fu-T'ang; Professor Lin Chiao-chih; Dr. Maxwell and his tablet; Francis R. Dieuaide; Charles Packard; A.B. Macallum; Tseng; Hsien-Tsang; Lorin Webster; W.W. Stifler; Sung-Tao Kwan; A.E. Severinghaus; Faculty of Premedical School; Bernard E. Read; Reid Hunt; J. Heng Liu; F.R. Dieuaide; Ernest C. Faust; A ward at the Peking Municipal Psychopathic Hospital; Senior Medical Students in louse-proof gowns serving in the emergency field hospital at Nanyuan
  - Malaria - Today (Box 17, Folder 428)
    "Status of Malaria Eradication Programs"; "De Laveran aux Consequences Medicales, Sociales, et Economiques de sa Decouterte" by P. Pene
  - Unknown Viruses (Box 17, Folder 429)
    "A Preliminary Progress Report Outlining the Principal Features of Venezuelan Equine Encephalitis Virus Outbreaks in the Departamento del Valle, Colombia" by Dr. Weir (includes photos); "Serological Survey in Northern Nigeria, by Hemagglutination-Inhibition Test" submitted by Jordi Casals; "Report from the California State Department of Public Health and the Rockefeller Foundation Arbovirus Study Unit, Berkeley, California"; "Operating Programs" from the RF Annual Report, 1962; "Belem Virus Laboratory, Progress Report, January-March 1966"; "Belem Virus Laboratory, Progress Report, January-July, 1962"; "Unknown Viruses by George W. Gray; "The Rockefeller Foundation Virus Program: 1951-1971 with Update to 1981" by Wilbur G. Downs; "The Rockefeller Foundation Virus Program: 1951-1971, Antecedents and Continuation" by Wilbur G. Downs
  - Publisher - Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 430)
  - MS Review - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 431)
  - Robert S. Northrup (Box 18, Folder 432)
  - EFD Program (Box 18, Folder 433)
    Rockefeller Foundation, Sanitary Engineering/Health Sciences
  - Unfoldered Materials (Box 18, Folder 434)
    "Penicillin Chronology" compiled by Dean H. Mayberry; Medical Education in Thailand, Prince Mahidol; "Wilder Graves Penfield, 1891-1976" by Sir John Eccles and William Feindel
  - Academic Medicine, Present and Future, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 435)
    Rockefeller Archive Center Conference, Correspondence
  - Notes and Bibliographies (Box 18, Folder 436)
  - Chapter 1, Master, "The Genesis" (Box 18, Folder 437)
  - Chapter 2, Master, "Hookworm and Sanitation" (Box 18, Folder 438)
  - Chapter 3, Master, "Schools of Public Health" (Box 19, Folder 439)
  - Chapter 4, Master, "The Attack on Malaria" (Box 19, Folder 440)
  - Chapter 5, Master, "Medical Education" (Box 19, Folder 441)
  - Chapter 6, Master, "China" (Box 19, Folder 442)
  - Chapter 7, Master, "Yellow Fever" (Box 19, Folder 443)
  - Chapter 8, Master, "The Unknown Viruses" (Box 19, Folder 444)
  - Chapter 8, Master, "The Unknown Viruses" (Box 20, Folder 445)
  - Chapter 9, Master, "Psychiatry" (Box 20, Folder 446)
  - Chapter 10, Master, "Natural Sciences - The New Biology" (Box 20, Folder 447-448)
  - Chapter 11, Master, "Community Medicine" (Box 20, Folder 449)
  - Chapter 12, Master, "Family Planning and Reproductive Biology" (Box 21, Folder 450)
  - Chapter 13, Master, "Schistosomiasis" (Box 21, Folder 451)
  - Chapter 14, Master, "Great Neglected Diseases" (Box 21, Folder 452)
  - "De Laveran aux Consequences Medicales, Sociales, et Economiques de sa Decouverte" (Box 21, Folder 453)
  - Natural Sciences - Final Drafts, Sections 1-5, "Natural Sciences - The New Biology" (Box 21, Folder 453A)
  - Natural Sciences - Final Drafts, Sections 1-5, "Natural Sciences - The New Biology" (Box 22, Folder 454)
  - Natural Sciences - Final Drafts, Sections 6-10, "Natural Sciences - The New Biology" (Box 22, Folder 455)
  - "Natural Sciences - The New Biology" Draft (Box 22, Folder 457)
  - Alberto Missiroli (Box 22, Folder 458)
    "Alberto Missiroli"; Translations
  - J.C. Meakins Obituary (Box 22, Folder 459)
  - Alan Gregg (Box 22, Folder 460)
    "A Natural History of Changing Your Job" by Alan Gregg; "Our Anabasis" by Alan Gregg
  - China: The Oral History of John B. Grant - Columbia Draft (Box 23, Folder 431)
    Correspondence; "The Reminiscences of Dr. John B. Grant," oral history summary; "An Analysis of the Objectives, Techniques, and Accomplishments of Dr. John B. Grant in Establishing the First Health Station of Peking, China" by James. D Grant; "The Faber Report on Medical Schools in China and After; Rockefeller Foundation, Quarterly Summary Report of Activities Relating to China, September 24, 1980; Photo, John B. Grant, Mrs. John B. Grant, Dr. Borislav Borcic
  - J.C. Snyder, Typhus, World War II (Box 23, Folder 462)
    "Typhus Fever in the Second World War" by J.C. Snyder
  - Wilder Penfield (Box 23, Folder 463)
    "Wilder Penfield (1891-1976): The Man and His Work" by William Feindel; "Montreal Neurological Institute/Montreal Neurological Hospita, 1934-1974, 'Memorabilia'"; "Wilder Penfield (1891-1976): Papers Given at a Memorial Meeting, 1976"
  - Walter Bradford Cannon and the RF (Box 23, Folder 464)
    "New Technology for a New Century: Walter B. Cannon and the Invisible Rays" by A. Clifford Barger; Photocopies of documents from the Walter B. Cannon Archive, Countway Library of Medicine
  - Royal Commission on Medical Education in the UK (Box 23, Folder 465)
    Photocopy, Royal Commission on University Education in London, November 1911
  - Schools of Public Health (Box 23, Folder 466)
    Notes on Turkey, Poland, Toronto, Bulgaria, Spain, Greece, Denmark, Norway, Sweden, Philippines, Michigan
  - Lowell Coggeshall Interview (Box 23, Folder 467)
  - Welch-Rose Report, Schools of Public Health (Box 23, Folder 468)
    "Institute of Hygiene, being a report by Dr. William H. Welch and Wickliffe Rose to the General Education Board, Submitted in 1915"
  - Simon Flexner (Box 23, Folder 469)
    "Statement Concerning a Memoir Dealing with Dr. Simon Flexner and His World, Submitted by James Thomas Flexner"
  - Yellow Fever (Box 23, Folder 470)
    "The Rockefeller Foundation Virus Program: 1951-1971 with Update to 1981" by Wilbur G. Downs; "The Story of Yellow Fever since Walter Reed" by Wilbur G. Downs; "A History of the Activities of the Rockefeller Foundation in the Investigation and Control of Yellow Fever" by Wilbur A. Sawyer; "Carlos Finlay and the Carrier of Death: The Cycle of Successful Scientific Discovery" by Juan Angel del Regato; "Jesse William Lazear, '92" by J.A. del Regato; "History of the Importation of Yellow Fever into the United States, from 1693-1878" by Samuel Choppin; Correspondence, Purnell Choppin, Hugh H. Smith (comments on yellow fever chapter); "The Development of Vaccines against Yellow Fever" by Max Theiler; "John C. Bugher, M.D."; "The Etiology of Yellow Fever. An Additional Note." by Walter Reed, James Carroll, and Aristides Agramonte; "Clara Loise Maass (1876-1901) et la Fièvre Jaune" by Lucie Arvy; "Some Aspects of Yellow Fever in Barbados, 1840-1912, submitted to the Rockefeller Foundation by Frank C. Ramsey; "Yellow Fever Surveys in Central America, Mexico, and Panama: 1941 and 1942" by Henry W. Kumm; "Theiler: Yellow Fever's Second Exit" from "First Big Break-through in Vaccines"; Miscellaneous Yellow Fever Articles
  - Psychiatry, Source Material (Box 23, Folder 471)
    "What is Psychiatry?" by Alan Gregg; "History of the Department of Psychiatry at Duke University" by James F. Gifford, Jr. and Eric Pfeiffer; "Fifty Years in Psychiatry: A Living History" by Roy R. Grinker, Sr.; "Report" by W. Grey Walter (Maudsley, 1938)
  - Faber Report (Box 23, Folder 472)
    "League of Nations Health Organisation Report on Medical Schools in China" by Knud Faber
  - Community Medicine, Gadjah Mada University (Box 23, Folder 473)
    "Comprehnsive Community Health Care: A Descriptive Syllabus of an Education Program for Students of Medicine," Gadjah Mada University; "Teaching Community Medicine to Doctors: Observations on the Gadjah Mada Experience" by Robert S. Northrup and Ron E. Rohde (RF Field Staff); "The Medical Faculty at Gadjah Mada University, Yogyakarta, Indonesia: A Review by the Rockefeller Foundation" by Northrup and Rohde
  - Arbovirus (Box 24, Folder 474)
    "The Program of the Department of Virology of the Naval American Medical Research Unit, Cairo, Egypt" by R.M. Taylor; "Virus Research Centre, Indian Council of Medical Research, Poona, India: A Handbook" (1975); "National Institute of Virology, Indian Council of Medical Research, Pune, India: Handbook" (1978); Diary Excerpts, Wilbur G. Downs: Halstead; "About Wil Downs" by Robert E. Shope; YARU Annual Report, 1966, Alphabetical List of Arthropod-Borne Viruses; "A Short Vocabulary of Virology" by Isabel Morgan Mountain; Diary Excerpts, Wilbur G. Downs - TRVL (Trinidad); Trinidad Regional Virus Laboratory, Quarterly Report, January-March 1959
  - Carlos Finlay, Yellow Fever (Box 24, Folder 475)
    "Oswaldo Cruz and the Impact of Yellow Fever on Brazilian History" by Donald B. Cooper (1967); "Centenary of the Graduation of Dr. Carlos J. Finlay in Jefferson Medical College" booklet; Photocopies from "The Evolution of Modern Medicine" by William Osler ("Sanitation"); "Adrian Stokes and Yellow Fever Research: A Tribute" by N. Paul Hudson; "Carlos Finlay and the Carrier of Death" by J.A. del Regato
  - Austin Kerr, Yellow Fever in the Americas: 1878-1917, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 476)
    "Yellow Fever in the Americas - 1878-1917" by Fred Lowe Soper, Part I: Prelude to the Prevention of Yellow Fever, 1878-1901"; "Yellow Fever in the Americas - 1878-1917" by Fred Lowe Soper, Part II: The Conquest of Yellow Fever Begins, 1900-1917"
  - Reprints and Xeroxes (Box 24, Folder 477)
    "On the Japanese B-West Nile Virus Complex or An Arbovirus Problem of Six Continents: by Telford H. Work; "The Program of the Department of Virology of the naval American Medical Research Unit, Cairo, Egypt" by R.M. Taylor; "A Tribute to Dick and Mary Taylor" by Telford Work; "Arboviruses Infecting Humans and Lower Animals in Egypt: A Review of Thirty Years of Research" by Medhat Darwish and Harry Hoogstraal; "Medical Education and Practice in Hong Kong" by Francis E. Stock; "A History of Medicine in Hong Kong" by Gerald H. Choa; "Harvard Medical Alumni Bulletin," Christmas 1963; "Phoenix of Physiology and Medicine: Franklin Chambers McLean" by Marshall R. Urist; "Ground Itch and Dew Poison; The Rockefeller Sanitary Commission 1909-14" by Mary Boccacio; "The Osmosis of Research: Example of the Cort Hookworm Investigations" by Norman R. Stoll; "Memorandum on The Health Organization of the League of Nations and the Relationship Thereto of the International Health Division of the Rockefeller Foundation" by George K. Strode; "Ernest Henry Starling: The Clinician's Physiologist" by Carleton B. Chapman; "My Scientific Odyssey" by John C. Eccles; "Walter Bradford Cannon, George Higginson Professor of Physiology" by Joseph Garland; "History of the Institute of Hygiene" by Victor C. Valenzuela and Teodora V. Tiglao (Philippines); "Johns Hopkins Hospital Bulletin, February 1900"; "Confidential Report on Institute of Hygiene and Schools of Public Health in Europe" by A.J. Warren; "Survey Report of the Medical School at the University of Oxford": "Modern Errors of Metabolism, 1. Archibald Garrod and the Birth of an Idea" by Alexander G. Bearn; "The Life and Works of Sir Archibald Garrod" by C.J.R. Hart; "University of Hongkong, The Rockefeller Endowment, Correspondence"; "Catalogue and Announcement, Harvard University School of Public Health" (1919, 1913); "The Rockefeller Foundation and the Development of Scientific Medicine in Great Britain" by Donald Fisher
  - Medical Education on a World-Wide Scale, Chapter 5 (Box 24, Folder 478)
  - Medicine and Public Health in China, Chapter 6 (Box 24, Folder 479)
  - Medicine and Public Health in China, Chapter 6 (Box 25, Folder 480)
  - Yellow Fever, Chapter 7 (Box 25, Folder 481)
  - Great Neglected Diseases, Chapter 14 (Box 25, Folder 482)
  - Family Planning, Chapter 12 (Box 25, Folder 483)
  - Community Medicine, Chapter 11 (Box 26, Folder 484)
  - Epilogue (Box 26, Folder 485)
  - Psychiatry, Chapter 9 (Box 26, Folder 486)
  - China - Source Material (Box 26, Folder 487)
    Infectious Diseases, China, Notes; "The Faculty of Medicine" by Lindsay Ride; "The Beginnings" by George Endacott; "From Models to Training Programs: The Rockefeller Effort" by James C. Thomson, Jr.; "RF History Source Material, Vol. VII, Creation of the China Medical Board (1914-1917)
  - Henry Lester (Box 26, Folder 488)
    "A Great Crisis" by F.L. Hawks Pott; Obituary, H.G. Earle
  - Yoshio Kusama Biographical Materials (Box 26, Folder 489)
  - Arbovirus Notes (Box 27, Folder 490)
  - Yellow Fever Barbados, Schistosomiasis, Population, Community Medicine Notes (Box 27, Folder 491)
  - Psychiatry Notes (Box 27, Folder 492)
  - Natural Sciences Notes (Box 27, Folder 493)
  - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission, International Health Division Hookworm, Hopkins School of Public Health, War Relief Commission, Public Health Labs, Sao Paulo, Malaria, IHD Research Russell Notes (Box 27, Folder 494)
  - Medical Education Notes (Box 27, Folder 495)
  - Schools of Public Health, Psychiatry Notes (Box 27, Folder 496)
  - China, Chapter 6 (Box 27, Folder 497)
  - Deletions - RF History (Box 27, Folder 498)
  - Outlines and Reports (Box 28, Folder 499)
  - Genesis, Chapter 1 (Box 28, Folder 500)
  - Public Health, Chapter 3 (Box 28, Folder 501)
  - Medical Education, Chapter 5 (Box 28, Folder 502)
  - Malaria, Chapter 4 (Box 28, Folder 503)
  - Warren Weaver and the Natural Sciences (Box 28, Folder 504)
  - Psychiatry, Chapter 9 (Box 29, Folder 505)
  - The Unknown Viruses, Chapter 8 (Box 29, Folder 506)
  - Volume 3, Chapters 11-14 (Box 29, Folder 507-508)
  - Volume 1, Chapters 1-7 (Box 30, Folder 509-510)
  - Natural Sciences, Chapter 10 (Box 30, Folder 511)
  - Hookworm and Genesis, Chapter 1 (Box 30, Folder 512)
- Medicine in Japan, 1 Cubic Feet
  This small series contains research and reference materials related to Bowers' writings on medicine in Japan. Files include reprints, articles, notes, and translations.
  - Notes and Photocopies (Box 30, Folder 513)
  - Willis - Reimeiki no Meiji (Box 30, Folder 514)
  - Sato Taizen, Articles by Ogawa Teizo (Box 30, Folder 515)
  - Unfoldered Japanese Manuscript (Photocopy) (Box 31, Folder 516)
  - Observations et Experiences, Jean de Carro (Box 32, Folder 517)
- Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission History, 1.9 Cubic Feet
  This series contains research and reference materials related to Bowers' history of the Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, later known as the Radiation Effects Research Foundation. Files include reprints, articles, notes, and drafts.
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation (Box 32, Folder 518)
    "Radiation Effects Research Foundation, Hoshasen Eikyo Kenkyusho, Origins and Growth, 1975-1983" (draft)
  - Non-Science, 1962-1975 (Box 32, Folder 519)
    Radiation Effects Research Foundation, Drafts and Correspondence
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation, Chronology of Events, 1945-1984 (Box 32, Folder 520)
  - Beebe (Box 32, Folder 521)
    "Experimental Studies on the Biological Actin of Hard Roentgen Rays" by Masao Tsuzuki; Correspondence
  - Bios - ABCC / NRC / Bronk (Box 32, Folder 522)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation Short (Box 32, Folder 523)
    "Radiation Effects Research Foundation: Hoshasen Eikyo Kenkyusho"
  - General Crawford Sams (Box 32, Folder 524)
    "Medic" by Crawford F. Sams; Portrait of Crawford F. Sams; "A Curriculum Vitae of RG Crawford Fountain Sams, MC" by Albert Ray Pacer; Correspondence and Notes
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation Completion (Box 32, Folder 525)
  - Notebook, Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission (Box 32, Folder 526)
  - Notebook, Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission / Radiation Effects Research Foundation (Box 33, Folder 527)
  - Draft (Box 33, Folder 528)
  - Chapter 3, 1951-1957 (Box 33, Folder 529)
  - Pediatrics - Miller (Box 33, Folder 530)
    "Radiation, Chromosomes, and Viruses in the Etiology of Leukemia: Evidence from Epidemiologic Research" by Robert W. Miller; "Induced Chromosomal Aberrations in Man" by Arthur D. Bloom; "Frequency of Marriage and Live Birth Among Survivors Prenatally Exposed to the Atomic Bomb" by William J. Blot Yukiko Shimizu, Hiroo Kato, and Robert W. Miller; "Late Radiation Effects: Status and Needs of Epidemiologic Research" by Robert W. Miller; "Mental Retardation Following 'In Utero' Explosure to the Atomic Bombs of Hiroshima and Nagasaki" by William J. Blot and Robert W. Miller; "Delayed Radiation Effects in Atomic-Bomb Survivors" by Robert W. Miller; "Small Head Size After Atomic Irradiation" by Robert W. Miller and John J. Mulvihill; "Distant Visual Acuity Loss Among Japanese Grammar School Children: The Roles of Heredity and the Environment" by Robert W. Miller; "Small Head Size After In-Utero Exposure to Atomic Radiation" by Robert W. Miller and William J. Blot; "Effects of Ionizing Raidation from the Atomic Bomb on Japanese Children" by Robert W. Miller; Notes; "Epidemiology Studies of Irradiated Populations" by Robert W. Miller
  - Arthur Bloom - Cytogenetics (Box 33, Folder 531)
    "Variation in the Human Chromosome Number" by A.D. Bloom, P.G. Archer, and A.A. Awa; "Biological Implications of the Cytogenetic Studies of A-Bomb Survivors" by A.D. Bloom and H.B. Hamilton; Domon-kai Photo, Kyushu University, 1979; "Hiroshima and Nagasaki: Three and a Half Decades of Genetic Screening" by William J. Schull, James V. Neel, Masanori Otake, Akio Awa, Chiyoko Satoh, and Howard B. Hamilton
  - Nagasaki, Notes (Box 33, Folder 532)
  - "The Story of the Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1946-1975" One-Page Summary (Box 33, Folder 533)
  - Biographies, Current (Box 33, Folder 534)
  - Walter Russell (Box 33, Folder 535)
    Correspondence; "Radiation Therapy Among A-Bomb Survivors" by Walter J. Russell and Shigetoshi Antoku; "Malignant Neoplasms Among Atomic Bomb Survivors Following Radiation Therapy" by J.A. Pinkston, S. Antoku, and W.J. Russell
  - Chapter 4, Darking Regime (Box 33, Folder 536)
  - Chapter 4, 1962-1975 (Box 33, Folder 537)
  - Hamilton (Box 34, Folder 538)
    Notes; "Japanese Noh Theater"; "Genetic Markers in the Atomic Bomb Survivors and their Children - Hiroshima and Nagasaki" by Howard B. Hamilton; "Interlaboratory Quality Control of Clinical Chemistry Values: Comparability in an Epidemiological Study" by Howard B. Hamilton; "Howard Hamilton: A Master of the Noh Theater"
  - Interviews (Box 34, Folder 539)
    Correspondence, Notes
  - Pedro Arrupe and the Atomic Bomb (Box 34, Folder 540)
    "P. Pedro Arrupe, S.J. and the Atomic Bomb, Hiroshima, with a Summary of His Life, 1907-1981. Also P. Siemes, S.J., Narrative of the Bomb" by John Z. Bowers and Akiko K. Bowers
  - Masao Tsuzuki (Box 34, Folder 541)
    "Atomic Bomb Injury from Medical Point of View" by Masao Tsuzuki; "Summary Report of Subcommittee on Medicine, Special Committee on Atomic Bomb Casualties and Damages" by Masao Tsuzuki; Notes and Translations
  - Hematology (Box 34, Folder 542)
    "Hematologic Studies in Hiroshima and a Control City: Two Years after the Atomic Bombing" by Fred M. Snell, James V. Neel, and K. Ishibashi
  - Francis Peter (Box 34, Folder 543)
    "Symposium: The Delayed Consequences of Exposure to Ionizing Radiation - Pathology Studies at the Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, Hiroshima and Nagasaki, 1945-1970"; Chart, Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission-Japanese National Institute of Health Unified Research Program Diretory; Notes
  - Shirabe, Nagasaki (Box 34, Folder 544)
    Notes; "Medical Survey of Atomic Bomb Casualties: by Raisuke Shirabe; "Round Table Discussion" by The Survivors of the Nagasaki Medical College relating their Personal Experience with Atomic Bomb Victims in Nagasaki
  - Genetics (Box 34, Folder 545)
    Notes; "Linkage in Man. Pelger's Nuclear Anomaly, Taste, and Blood Groups" by N.E. Morton, W.C. Moloney, and T. Fujii; "Data on Linkage of Ovalocytosis and Blood Groups" by T. Fujii, W.C. Moloney, and N.E. Morton; "The Inheritance of Human Birth Weight" by Newton E. Morton; "An Estimate of the Mutational Damage in Man from Data on Consanguineous Marriages" by Newton E. Morton, James F. Crow, and H.J. Miller; "A Cohort-Type Study of Survival in the Children of Parents Exposed to Atomic Bombings" by Hiroo Kato, William J. Schull, and James V. Neel; "Non-Randomness in Consanguineous Marriage" by Newton E. Morton
  - Cancer Society (Box 34, Folder 546)
  - Cytogenetics (Box 34, Folder 547)
    Correspondence and Photocopies; "Some Thoughts Regarding Cytogenetic Studies at ABCC"
  - Reprints (Box 34, Folder 548)